So, now, we have a simple service. Wasn't that easy?
But it still doesn't wake itself up. Fortunately, there's a system
service for that. This is a good opportunity to introduce
the AlarmManager. The AlarmManager allows you to tell the system that
you want it to wake a component of your application
up after a period of time and do some processing in
the background. You can even have it wake up your
application periodically but, what do we wake up in the background?
That would be an Android component we haven't
seen before called a Broadcast Receiver. A Broadcast Receiver
is a special class, that is used to
receive intent broadcast often from other applications. Typically a
broadcast receiver will register an intent filter for
these broadcasts. It's also one way the application will
listen in on alarms. So let's add some alarm
stuff. First, I'm going to add a Broadcast Receiver
as a static inner class of Sunshine Service.
Since this is an Android component, I'll register
this Broadcast Receiver in the manifest. Note the
way a static inner class is notated. Okay, I've
given you the bones of a broadcast receiver
that can handle an alarm, but now it's
your turn. You can create a PendingIntent from
an explicit intent to have the alarm manager activate
your broadcast receiver. I recommend setting the alarm to something absurdly
short, like five seconds, so you can easily test that it's working.